我是詹姆斯 提比略 柯克船长
My name is Captain James Tiberius Kirk.
来自星际联盟
United Federation of Planets
本次我作为一名中立代表
I came here before you as a neutral representative
代表佛博南共和国前来觐见
of the Fabonane Republic.
向你们致以诚挚的问候
And bring you a message of good will
并向您，尊敬的提纳兹代表团的各位
And present to you, esteemed members of the teenaxiene delegation
呈上这份来自佛博南最高议会充满诚意的礼物
A gift from Fabonan High Council with the highest regard.
他脑子有毛病吧？
What's wrong with it?
- 您说什么？  - 他们为什么不要那玩意了？
- Excuse me?  - Why the don't they want it anymore?
这是某种上古武器的一块碎片
Well... This was once a piece of an ancient weapon
现在他们把它献给你们作为一种
And now they offer it as a symbol, of...
和平的象征
... of peace.
在佛博南的传统中主动奉上武器就意味着
In the Fabonan culture this surrendal weapon
请求休战
is an offer of truth.
那他们是怎么找到它的？
How they got it?
他们说这是他们很久以前得到的
They told me, they acquired it long time ago.
那这就是他们偷来的！
So they stole it, then!
不，他们...
No... the uhm...
其实
Well...
你们根本不像我们一样了解佛博南人
You don't know the Fabonan like we do !
您说的对，殿下，这份礼物...
That's very true.Your excellency, this gift...
他们是一群卑劣的小偷
They are crowds of untrustworthy thieves.
想看着我们被杀死在自家的床上
who wants to see us murdered in our own base.
这件无价之宝寄托了他们的信任和对和平的渴望
This beloved artifact is a symbol of trust and peace.
他们会把我们剁成碎块，再把我们放火上烤
They will cut us into pieces,and roast us over a fire...
我不认为那是真的...
I don't think that's true...
最后吃掉我们！
... and eat us !!
您说什么？
What ?!
斯科特，快把我弄出去！
Scotty!! Get me out of here!
这么快就好了！
Well, that was quick.
长官，你的表面有干扰物
There is quite a bit a surface interference, sir.
我又把制服撕破了
I ripped my shirt again.
谈判进展如何？
How'd it go?
长官，您和提纳兹人达成协议了吗？
Captain, did you manage to broke a treaty with the Teenaxi?
这么说吧，会谈没多久就结束了
Uhm... Let's just say we came out short.
史波克，你能帮我把这个锁回柜子里吗，谢谢
You look... move that back into the personal vault, Spock.Thank you.
- 吉姆，你看上去糟透了  - 谢谢夸奖，老骨头
- Jim, you look like crap.  - Thank you, Bones.
你太阳穴位置的静脉又明显凸起，你没事吧
You have a little vein popin out of your tremble again. You okay?
我很好，今天只不过又是星际舰队里无聊的一天罢了
Never better.It's just a another day in fleet.
航行日志, 星历2263.2.
Captain's Log, Stardate 2263.2
今天是我们在外太空航行的第966天
Today is our 966-day in deep space.
我们已经度过了五年任务中的三年
A little over 3 years of our 5 year mission.
我们呆在这的时间越长，我们就愈发感到
More time you spend out here, the harder it is
当一天结束之时，迎接新的一天的艰难
to tell when one day ends and the next one begins.
要在这要找到归属感极为困难
It can be a challenge to feel grounded
因为连重力本身都是人造的
when even gravity is artifical.
但我们会尽我们所能把这里变得像家一样
But while we do what we can to make it feel like home
船员们总是表现得极为完美
The crew is always continues to act admirably
尽管长期的外太空探险条件非常苛刻
despite the rigors of our extended stay here in outer space
同时他们也做出了许多牺牲
and the personal sacrifices they have made.
我们在持续找寻新的生命形式
We continue to search for new forms in order
并且建立起彼此之间牢固的外交关系
to establish firm diplomatic ties.
我们不断地探索未知领域
Understanding the time in uncharted territories
考验飞船的机械性能
stretched the ships mechanical capacities
幸运的是，由斯科特先生带领的工程团队
but fortunately, our engineering departement led by Mr.Scott
能很好地解决飞船的各类机械问题
...is more than up for the job.
除此之外，飞船上长期的同居生活
The ship aside, prolonged cohabitation has...
确实对我们之间的一些人际关系产生了影响
definitely infects on interpersonal dynamics.
有一些如胶似漆
Some experience is for better...
有一些则不太妙
...and some for worse.
至于我自己，我越来越觉得自己变得有些
As for me things have started to feel
有些多虑
little episodic.
随着我们对宇宙的不断探索，我开始思考这样一个问题
Futher out we go, the more I find myself wondering
我们究竟想要的是什么
what is it we are trying to accomplish.
如果宇宙真的是无穷无尽的
If the universe is trully endless, then...
那我们努力去到达的正是我们无法抵达的地方
...if we're not striving for something forever out of reach.
进取号正在取得在约克城停靠的许可
The Enterprise is scheduled for repremission to stop at Yorktown,
那是星际联邦最新最先进的星舰基地
Federation's newest and most advanced starbase.
也许这个小小的休假能让我们从
Perhaps a break from routine will offer us some rest, but...
那些神秘事件与未知生物中抽身片刻
...not from mysteries, the unknown.
抱歉，我迟到了
Sorry, I'm late.
昆赛尔正在呼出某种绿色的酸性卤素液体
Keenser's weakend by some hallious seed green flu...
斯科特吓坏了，怕他一个喷嚏打在飞船的主核心上
...and Scotty is terrified, he's gonna sneeze on warp core
我们就都完了
and kill us all.
你他丫的在喝什么？
What the hell are you drink?
我很确定这是我们从赛塔斯带回来剩下的索里安白兰地
Pretty sure it's the rest of that Saurian brandy we picked up on Thasus.
天哪！你这是要把自己喝瞎吗？
My god man! Are you trying to go blind?
这东西可是违法的
That stuff's illegal.
不过，我在契科夫的柜子里发现了这个
Besides, I found this in Chekov's locker.
哇
Wow!
好极了，我一直在想，他可是喝伏特加的
Right, I mean I always assumed he would be Vodka guy...
没错，伏特加
Vodka guy. Exactly.
我一直想为你生日准备一些像样的东西
I wanted to have something appropriate for your birthday.
还有还多天呢，你不必着急
It's a couple of days, you know I don't care about that.
我明白，你不喜欢庆祝自己的生日
I know. You don't like celebrating it to on the day...
因为那天正好也是你父亲的忌日
...because it's also the day your pop bit the dust.
我能理解你的心情
I was being sensitive.
你在上医学院的时候就从没人教过你怎么好好说话吗？
Did they teach you about better manner at medical school?
又或者说这只是你南方人的特色？
Or it's just a sudden charm?
- 这酒好极了  - 可不是么
- Oh yeah. Ooh. That's good.  - Lordy.
你要给你的母亲打给电话么
You're gonna call your mom?
当然，到了那天我肯定会打的
Yeah, of course I'll call on the day.
我又老了一岁
I'm an year older.
是啊，生日不就这意思么
Yeah, that's usually how it works.
比他原来的年龄又多了一岁
A year older than he ever got to be.
他加入了星际舰队，因为
He joined the Starfleet because he...
他有信念
...he believed in it.
我来这不过是一时上头罢了
I joined on a dare.
你来这是为了不辜负他的期望
You joined this if you can live up to him.
你花了这么多时间向你的父亲乔治 科克看齐
It's been all this time, you are trying to be George Kirk...
到头来你却在想为什么活不出自己的特色
...and now you're wondering just what it means to be Jim...
在想自己为什么进入星际舰队
...why you're out here.
敬完美的你，至少你还有一头黑发
To prove that aside and a full head of hair.
- 我是柯克  - 船长
- Kirk here. - Captain.
- 正在接近约克城基地  - 我马上过去，苏鲁先生
- Approaching Yorktown base.  - I'm on my way, Mr. Sulu.
生日的事请为我保密
Let's keep this birthday thing in a wraps something.
明白，敏感先生
You know me.Mr. Sensitive.
真是壮观极了
Woaah, that is impressive.
没错，她是个大美人，对吧
Ay. She is a beauty, isn't she?
真是个畸形的怪物
What a damn monstrosity.
我们能在这个星球上租几块地吗
Can't we just wrap some space on a planet?
在星联星球间表露出地域偏好
Sharing geographical favouritism among conducted Federation worlds
可能会导致外交紧张
could cause diplomatic tension.
你不认为它看上去都挤在一起了么
Oh, you don't think that looks tense?
它只是太空中一个混蛋的大雪球，等着我们去打碎而已
Looks like a damn snow globe in space just waiting to break.
那它就消失了，老骨头
Ah, that's the spirit, Bones!
史波克！
Spock!
你现在有空吗
Do you have a moment?
当然了，尼欧塔
Of course, Nyota.
我得把这个还给你
You should have this back.
这毕竟是你母亲的遗物
It belonged to your mother.
我们瓦肯人从不收回
It is not in a Vulcan custom...
已经送出去的礼物，这是传统
...to receive again that thing which was given as a gift.
你们分手了？
You guys break up?
你做了啥错事？
What did you do?
你的推理过于简单了，医生
A typically reductive incourin out to.
听我说，史波克，如果一个地球女孩跟你说她错了，你没错
You know Spock,if an Earth girl says it's me not you.
那绝对是你错了
It's definitely you.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
史波克指挥官，你现在有空么？
Commander Spock.Will you have a minute of your time?
感谢您告知我此事
Thank you for bringing me this,into my attention.
生生不息 繁荣昌盛
Live long and prosper.
史波克大使，生于2230.06  卒于2263.02
Ambassador Spock，2230.06 - 2263.02
检测到一个正在靠近的飞行器
I have an alert of incoming vessel.
身份不明，非星联飞行器
Unidentified non-federation.
请注意，未知飞行器
Attention, unidentified vessel.
你未获取靠近许可
You are not authorized for approach.
关闭引擎 等待指示
Power down and wait for instruction.
未知飞行器 请回答
Unidentified vessel, please comply.
请用正常语速说话
Just speak normally.
语言分析完成
Language analysis complete
通用翻译
UNIVERSAL TRANSLATOR
我们在赛斯星云执行一个科学考察任务
We were on a science mission inside the nebula.
我们的飞船出现严重故障
Our ship suffered a critical malfunction.
我上了一个救生舱
I took an escape pod.
我们的飞船迫降在附近的一个星球上
Before the ship crash landed on a nearby planet.
我们需要一艘能在星云间航行的飞船
We need a ship,capable of navigating the nebula.
你必须派人来帮帮我们
You must have someone,who can help us.
我们试图在赛斯星云定位失事飞船，那是一片未知的星域，因此没有成功
We tracked her stranded ship through the sector of uncharted nebula.
坐标210，14
Here. 210, mark 14.
远距扫描有结果吗？
Long-range scan?
没有，那片未知星云过于密集了
No data. The nebula is too dense.It's uncharted space.
进取号的导航系统是全舰队中最先进的
Well, the Enterprise does have the best navigational systems in the fleet.
她应该能完成这次救援任务
She can handle it.
唯一一艘比进取号更为先进的星舰
The only ship here,with more advanced technology...
仍然在建设中
...is still under construction.
我想说的是，我们要派过去的不仅仅是一艘星舰
But it's not just a ship that I am sending.
我马上集合船员
I'll gather the crew.
船长
Captain.
因为你目前在我管辖的星域里，星舰指挥部把你
Starfleet Command sent me your application for your vice-admiral position
提交的中将升职申请函发给我了
here at this installation.
我知道，女士
Yes, ma'am.
如果允许的话，我会推荐史波克指挥官
If I may, I would recommend Commander Spock...
接任我成为下一任进取号指挥官
to replace me as a Captain of the Enteprise.
他是一位模范星舰军官，他会是一位好船长的
He is an exemplary Starfleet officer.He'll make a great Captain.
你要知道，在星际舰队中，哪怕是在职的星舰舰长
It isn't uncommon, you know.
提交离职请求都是十分正常的
Even for a captain,to want to leave.
在广阔的宇宙中没有相对位置
There's no relative direction in the vastness of space...
只能靠你自己
...there's only yourself.
你的星舰和你的船员
Your ship, your crew.
很容易就在太空中迷失自我
It's easier than you think to get lost.
我会和最高理事会讨论你的申请
I'll really talk with the General Council.
等你回来我们再议
We'll discuss it, when you return.
- 史波克先生 - 船长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
- 我有些事... - 我想...
- I have something... - Perhaps there...
- 不，你先说 - 船长，你说完我再说
- No, please. - Captain, after you.
我坚持如此
I insist.
这次任务完成后
After this mission, we should...
我们得坐下来好好谈谈
...we should sit down.There is something I need to talk about.
我也想跟您好好谈谈
I, as well, have something to share.
我们合作愉快，没错吧？
We make a good team, right?
我对此深信不疑
I believe we do.
我坚持你先走
I insist.
乌胡拉中尉，打开全船广播
Lt. Uhura, open a ship wide channel.
是，船长
Yes, Captain.
全体进取号船员注意
Attention, crew of the Enterprise.
我们这次任务目的明确
Our mission is straightforward.
到一片未知星域中营救一艘失事飞船的船员
The rescue of a crew stranded on a planet in uncharted space.
我们的航线会经过一片不稳定的星云
Our trajectory will take us through an unstable nebula...
届时我们将会中断同星际舰队总部的所有联系
...one which will disable all communication with Starfleet.
我们只能依靠我们自己
We will be on our own.
请记住进取号有着其它星舰都没有的东西
The Enteprise has something no other ship in the fleet has.
那就是各位船员们
You.
我一直坚信没有什么是未知的
As we can't understand there's no such space, the unknown.
只不过是暂时不为人知罢了
We'll be temporarily hidden.
柯克广播结束
Kirk out.
度数显示星云密度正在降低，长官
Readings indicate cloud density deminishing, sir.
那就是奥尔塔米德，我的飞船就迫降在那
This is Altamid.Our ship is stranded here.
接近奥尔塔米德星球
Approaching Altamid.
星球等级M
Class M planet.
地底活动较为活跃，但是表面几乎没有任何生命体存在
Massive subterranean fauna, with unlimited unknown life forms on the surface...
距离警报，长官
Proximity alert, sir.
有一艘未知飞船正在靠近我们
We have an unknown ship heading right on us.
- 乌胡拉中尉，呼叫他们 - 是，船长
- Lt. Uhura, hail them. - Yes, Captain.
没有回复
No response.
什么信号都收不到
I'm picking up some kind of a signal.
我们这是被干扰了吧
They are jamming us.
苏鲁先生，放大图像
Magnify, Mr. Sulu.
这是什么？
What is this?
打开防护罩！拉响警报！
Shields up! Red alert!
自由开火！
Fire at will!
长官，相位炮效果过于微弱
Sir, our phasers are having minimal effect
我们的鱼雷无法探测到敌人的移动轨迹
and our torpedoes can't track the movement.
把所有能打的都打出去
Fire everything we've got.
船长，我们所有的武器都无法胜任这种类型的交火
Captain, we are not equipped for this matteral engadgement.
防护罩对敌无效，长官
Shields frequency has no effect, sir.
他们摧毁了我们的引擎
They got the DITCH.
防护罩失灵
Shields are offline.
- 启动曲速引擎离开这里，苏鲁先生 - 是，长官
- Warp us out of here, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
- 为什么飞船没有开始曲速移动？ - 长官，无法启动曲速引擎
- Why the hell aren't we moving? - I can not engage the warp drive, sir.
斯科特，马上去排查故障，我们要进入曲速状态
Scotty, I need warp now.
长官，我无法完成任务
I can not, sir.
引擎没了
...they are gone.
启动所有安全应急程序
Security, engage all emergency procedures.
所有人员到都去急救站报道
All personnel to emergency stations.
12层至15层发现船体破损
I have hull breaches in levels 12 to 15,
6.9.31.21层也发现船体破损
6, 9, 31 and 21, sir.
船长，我有个办法能从曲速引擎核心转移能量
Captain, in a 10 sec I could reroute the energy from the warp core
到推进器
to the impulse engines.
疏散所有人员
If we can get back into the nebula maybe we can lose them
放手去做吧，斯科特
Do whatever you have to, Scotty.
昆赛尔，跟我来
Keenser let's go.
道路清理完毕，克劳
All clear, krall.
这就是遗失的安布罗纳斯碎片
Connecting plasma pipes,stand by then you start it on my mark!
武器已经找全了
I have the Abronath.Secure the ship.
船长呼叫史波克
- Captain. - Go, Spock.
我发现了他们的一个长官，他似乎是这次进攻行动的总指挥
I've identified the individual intruder and leading the attack party.
他们潜入了档案室，拿走了我们
They infiltrated the archive vault,and removed the artifact
原本打算赠送给提纳兹星球的手工品
from our mission on Teenax.
坚持住，我们马上...
Hold your idstance until...
史波克！史波克！
Spock! Spock!
你们俩跟我来，苏鲁，你来临时指挥
You two, with me.Sulu, you are commanding officer.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我的天！
My god!
这是什么情况！
...the hell?
医生？
Doctor?
医生，我们得撤了
Doctor, we must evacuate now!
柯克
Captain
船长
Kirk
推进器充能完毕
Yes!We have 100% impulse.
斯科特先生，干的漂亮
Great work, Mr. Scott!
启动推进器，驶向星云
Maximum impulse towards the nebula!
是
Ay!
克劳，他们要逃进星云去了
Krall, the ship runs into nebula.
割开他们的喉咙
Cut it's neck.
柯克呼叫舰桥
Kirk to bridge.
惯性阻尼器已损坏
We are losing the innertial dampers.
船长，全船系统都崩溃了
Systems are failing throughout the ship, Captain.
应急面板已激活
The emergency blockades are sealing...
但全船结构完整性只有18%并正在降低，长官！
...but the structural integrity is at 18% and falling, sir.
苏鲁先生，全员弃船
Abandon ship, Mr. Sulu.
拉响警报
Sound the alarm.
我们要给这些救生舱逃走创造机会
Maybe in those Pods it's a chance to escape
到时候你能把飞船开远点么
Can you lead the ship away?
推进器还在从备用的曲速引擎核心汲取能量
The impulse engines are still trying to draw power from the warp reserve.
在启动碟形分离程序前我们都动不了
We can not move until the SAUCER is separated.
我来搞定这个
I'll handle it.
好的，长官
Ay ay, sir.
赶快把他们带到救生舱去，快去
We got to get you guys to escape pod. Go.
希尔少尉
Ensign. Syl.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
天啊！
My god!
史波克，他们正在抓船员！
Spock, they are taking the crew.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
飞船碟形部分应该没人了
SAUCER should be free by now.
我明白，苏鲁先生，但船长应该就在那边
I know, Mr. Sulu.The Captain should be there.
碟形部分已分离
SAUCER SEPARATION
推动引擎现在改由辅助发电机驱动了
The impulse engines drawing power from auxiliary generators.
船长
Captain.
碟形区那边还有船员吗
How many of the crew is still pod disposal?
没了
None.
如果这些仪器工作正常的话
If I read this correctly...
入侵者正在抓捕船员
...the intruders are taking them.
船长，我们被星球重力吸引了
Captain, we're caught in the planet's gravity.
我们开不走了
We can not pull away.
你们上救生舱吧
Get your captain pods.
是，长官
- Yes, sir. - Ay, Captain.
快，我们走
Come on! Let's go!
你早就
You knew...
知道我们会被袭击
You knew we would be attacked.
你还不明白现在发生的一切
You don't understand.
柯克船长
Captain Kirk.
是的，我撒谎了
Yes, I lied.
我的飞船也被攻击了
Our ship was attacked.
契科夫，找一找有没有生还者的信号
Chekov, check your comms for survivors.
是，长官
Ay ay, ay Captain.
- 他是什么人？ - 他叫克劳
- Who is he? - His name is Krall.
他抓走了我的船员，也抓走了你的
He took my crew,like he took yours.
他怎么会对进取号那么了解？
How did he know so much about the Enterprise?
我只知道我按他说的把你们引到这里来
All I know is that if I did this...
他就会放走我的船员
...he'll set them free.
契科夫，扫描仪上发现了信号吗？
Chekov, are you picking anything upon those scanners?
没有，长官
Nothing.
- 他们会不会已经... - 不会的
- What if he... - No, no.
他们肯定活下来了
He was taking them.
我们得找到飞船的碟形部
We have to find that SAUCER even
你可以利用船上的扫描仪，扫描范围比你手上的三角仪大多了
minimal scanning systems will have longer range than tricorders.
好的，船长，这个方案是可行的
Ay, Captain. It's possible.
船长，我这么做只是为了保护我的船员
Captain, I was protecting my crew.
你叫什么？
What is your name?
你怎么会说我的语言？
How do you know our language?
我还很了解你们这个物种呢
I know your kind.
我是进取号通讯官，妮欧塔 乌胡拉
I'm Lt. Nyota Uhura of the USS Enteprise.
你已经发起了一场战争对抗联...
And you have committed an act of war against Fede...
星际联邦
Federation.
星际联邦就是战争的代名词
Federation is an act of war.
你攻击了我们
You've attacked us.
你的船长...
Your captain...
为什么你会牺牲自己去救他？
Why did you sacrifice yourself for him?
换做他，在这种情况下他也会这么做
He would have done the same.
如果他从船上逃走了，他就会来救我们
And if he made it off that ship,he will come for us.
我正指望着他来呢，乌胡拉中尉
I'm counting on it, Lt. Uhura.
简直难以置信
I can't believe it.
我的天，史波克！
My god, Spock!
赶紧到那边走下来
Sit down over here.
慢点，慢点
Okay, easy, easy.
行，我现在打算...
I'll just a...
你放松就好，没事的
Try to relax.Your're going to be okay.
你语气里那种不自然的乐观
Forced optimism in your voice suggests
表明你正努力让自己进入平静状态...
you are trying to enlist essensive calm in order...
省省你这些垃圾话吧
Cut the horse shit.
医生，就目前情况来看，我们应该尽力寻找
Doctor. I failed to see how excrement of any kind feels relevance
其他的幸存船员
in our current situation.
- 你他丫的在干什么？ - 我们应该马上开始行动
- What the hell are you doing? - We must keep moving, doctor.
史波克，这玩意都刺穿了你的腹部了
Spock, this thing punched your iliac region.
- 时间是十分重要的 - 我还正想跟你说这个呢
- Time is a critical factor. - That's exactly what I am trying to tell you.
听着，如果我不把这东西拔出来，你就死定了
Look, I can't take this out.You are gonna die.
如果我把这东西拔出来，但是止不住血，你也死定了
Okay, if I take it out and can't stop the bleeding, you are gonna die.
我能不能两个都不选
I can't see no appealing neither option.
你没得选，我也没得选
Believe me or not,neither can I.
嗯，如果我没记错的话
So, if I remember correctly
瓦肯人心脏和人类肝脏的位置是一样的
you got Vulcans of your hearts,where humans have their livers.
你说的没错，医生
That is correct, doctor.
怪不得
That explains some things.
你知道你运气有多好么，如果那玩意扎的位置再往左移两寸
You know, you are lucky.Two centimeters to the left...
你早就死了
...and you would be dead already.
我真是想不通，史波克
I just don't get it, Spock.
他们为啥要攻击我们
What did they attack us for?I mean...
他们吃饱了没事就以跟别人开战为乐么
They do all this for some duedad with the tiny clevers didn't want?
藐视一个你不了解的人的意图是不明智的，医生
It is unwise to trivialize that which one simply does not understand, Doctor.
我们只能简单的假设说他们的目的肯定不简单
We can safely assume that it's more important than a duedad.
你居然用一句话嘲讽了我两次，史波克
I think you just managed to insult me twice, Spock.
好了，史波克
Alright, Spock.
最后问你一个问题
Just got one question.
- 你最喜欢的颜色是什么？ - 我不明白你为什么突然问...
- What's your favorite color? - I failed to see the relevance...
他们告诉我说感到惊讶时你就不会觉得很痛了
Yeah, they say it hurts less if it's a surprise.
如果要我用我们都熟悉的说法来形容
I made a doctor parlance with which you are familiar...
你所说的，我觉得你说的说法就是“垃圾”
...I can confirm your theory to be horse shit.
我们走
We gotta get out of here.
这他妈的就是在逗我
You're kidding me, aren't you?
你们好
Hello there.
我是蒙哥马利 斯科特
My name is Montgomery Scott... and...
你们是？
...who might you be?
注意点，你们这些家伙，我可比你们想象的身手好多了
Watch it sonny,I am pretty handy when I want to be... right.
别再来找我麻烦了
No come back.
美女，身手不错啊
Well, we surely show *something*
这些是舰队的财产，你不能就这么拿走了...
Hey! That's Starfleet property...You can not just take them and....
但是我今天心情很好你就随便拿吧
...but, I'm feeling generous today so have at it.
那玩意你是在哪找到的？
Where did you get that?
- 你会说英语？ - 我在我房子里学会的，你这玩意在哪拿的？
- Is that English? - I learned it from my house. Where did you get that ?
- 这是我的星舰军官徽章 - 那是什么意思？
- This is my Starfleet insignia. - What does it mean ?
它代表着我是一位来自星舰轮机部的军官
Means that I am an officer of a Starfleet's engineering division.
- 轮机部？ - 是的，我负责修东西
- Engineering? - Ay yes, I fix things.
我知道那是啥意思
I know what is engineering.
你知道是谁击落了我的飞船吧？
You're not with those bastards who killed my ship are ya?
我就当你不知道了
I take that as a no.
他叫克劳，他和他的...
He is Krall. He and his...
蜂群
...bees.
他们在找一个东西，一个杀人机器
They searched the stars for ya.Death machine.
这就是为什么你和我们所有人现在在这的原因
They are the reason why you are here,why we are all here.
也包括刚刚那些流氓吗？
Even those 3 scunners?
他们也是飞船坠毁的幸存者，就像你我一样
They have fallen from the sky,like me and you.
现在跟我走！
Come with me. Now!
等会，小姑娘，我今天过的很不顺
Wait, hang on a minute.I had a difficult day here.
我要去找我的朋友
I gotta fing my crewmates.
我会帮你找到你的朋友
I will help you find your mates...
然后你来帮我一个忙
...and then you will help me.
帮你什么？
With what?
- 你要我帮你修东西？ - 对
- You want me to fix something? - Yes.
你帮我，我就帮你
You help me and I help you.
那么，考虑到现在的情况，我看我是没得选了
Alright, well things have been nasty all day,and I won't get better offer today.
我跟你走
So lead the way.
很好
Good.
我叫婕拉
I am Jaylah.
- 你是蒙哥马利 斯科特 - 对，叫我斯考提就好（斯科特的昵称）
- And you're Montgomery Scott. - Ay, Scotty.
跟我走，蒙哥马利 斯考提
Come now, Montgomery Scotty.
等等我
Alright, hold up.
进取号
The Enterprise.
可能都无法为舰桥供电了，船长
It may not even have power to the bridge, Captain.
这个外星女人身上肯定还有不为人知的秘密
She still has a few tricks up her sleeve.
我敢打包票
I bet on it.
麦考伊呼叫进取号，收到请回答
McCoy to Enterprise, come in.
麦考伊呼叫进取号
McCoy to Enterprise.
走慢点，史波克，我只是临时缝合了一下
Hey, take it easy there, Spock.That was just a temporary fix back there.
知道了，医生
I understand, Doctor.
真是个迷人的洞穴
Fascinating.
胡说，明明是危险又黑暗的洞穴
Omuns, dark, dangerous.
不管怎么说我们还是进去吧
We are going in.
真是有趣
Intriguing.
这里的符号和袭击中被偷走的文物上的那些符号一模一样
These symbols are the same as those that we picked on the artifact taken in the attack.
你认为那个文物来自于这个星球？
You think it came from here?
看起来是这样
It would seem so.
史波克！
Damm it... Spock!
走快点
Hurry.
- 还有多远？ - 闭嘴，别问了
- Aren't we there yet? - Stop asking that.
- 抱歉 - 走这边，进来
- Sorry. - This is the way, come.
小心点，别掉到我的陷阱里去了
Watch your steps,you do not want to set up my traps.
哦，这真聪明
Oh, that's clever.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
- 这是我的房子 - 你的房子？
- This is my house. - Your house ?
这是一艘飞船吗？
Is this a ship?
我希望你能找到你的朋友们，然后你们来帮我修这艘飞船
I hope you find your friends and you help me fix it.
这样我就能永远的离开这个星球了
So I can leave this planet forever.
等等
Wo... Wait a minute.
这是你的船吗？
Is this your ship?
不，蒙哥马利 斯科特
No, Montgomery Scotty.
这是你们的船
It's yours.
我的天哪
Oh my good lord.
富兰克林号 星舰代码NX 326
U.S.S Franklin - Starfleet
船长，看起来船体已经彻底失去动力了
Captain, it looks like there is power.
好吧，我们到舰桥上去，想办法找到幸存的船员
Alright, let's get to the bridge and find the crew.
控制台完好无损，船长
The console is intacted, and I will...
我来试着重启它
...try to reroute power to it.
动作快点
Work fast.
启动这些仪器后，灯火通明的房间肯定会招来不少敌人
Once we get this place run,we are gonna draw a lot of attention.
怎么样？你能找到他们吗？
What do you think? You can find them?
我试试，船长
Ay, Captain.
我来重新配置一下扫描仪，调整一下频率
I am reconfiguring scanners to modulate for the crews sequence.
你跟我来，我在船上落下了点东西
You with me.I left something behind.
还好你感冒了，要不然我们就出不去了
That is one heck of a cold.
干的漂亮，昆赛尔
Nice job, Keenser.
动作快点，距离下一班哨兵轮岗还有15分钟
Alright, we got about 15 minutes until the next guard rotation.
快点
Come on.
快点跟上，走
Let's go, go.
快点
Come on!
这是一个麦哲伦探针
This is a Magellan probe.
星联用它们来寻找通往星云的航线
Federation is using these to find a way through the nebula.
克劳怎么会用到这个
What he is using it for?
你发现了什么？
What do you see?
他借助探针之间的子链路传递信息
He's been pinging back in a subspace links between the probes.
我们能利用这个发送求助信号吗
Well, use it to send a distress signal.
我试试看
I am trying.
信号已发送
Sent.
他访问过约克镇的数据库
He has access to Yorktown database.
你说什么？
What?
这些是星舰的数据库，相关文件
That's Startfleet datafiles... ship logs...
进取号的文件也包括在内
...including the Enterprise.
原来他一直在监视我们
He's been watching us this whole time.
船长
Captain...
这文物一直都放在船上吗？
...the artifact was on the ship the whole time?
我可不想带着它被人抓住
I cannot afford to get caught with it.
所以我就把它藏在这了
So I hid it in here.
告诉克劳，我拿到安布罗纳斯了
Tell Krall... I have the Abronath.
你是不是相信所有你听过的悲惨故事？
Do you really swallow my sad story you hear?
我可不会全信
Not every.
请把你手里的枪放下
Put the phaser down. Please.
找到了吗，契科夫
You get it, Chekov?
找到了，已经确认了与她通话人的位置
Ay, Captain. I've traced her location of her comm.
为什么克劳想要这东西？
What does Krall want with this thing?
他是来拯救你们的
To save you.
从你们内部
From yourselves.
长官！
Captain!
- 你还好么？ - 我很好，船长，但是我们已经被困住了
- You all right? - Ay, Captain, but we are trapped.
你能启动推进器吗？
Can you get this thing started?
你确定现在发动引擎？
Are you intending inition...  engage the thrusters?
你还有更好的办法么
I am open up for suggestions.
好吧
Okay.
- 现在有个问题 - 啥问题
- There's the problem, sir. - What?
管道出问题了，我没法让燃料燃烧
It's the pipe.I can not init to combust.
船长，现在情况很紧急
Captain, we are basically standing on a very large bomb.
如果你没打中燃料压缩机...
If you miss the combustion compressor.
我从不会失手，别说了
I am not gonna miss, come on.
你知道燃料压缩机长什么样么？
Do you even know how the compressor looks like?
是方形的吧？
As squared, right?
不，是圆形的
No, it's round.
刚好我打偏了！
That's what I said.
契科夫
Chekov!
契科夫，快跑！
Chekov, move!
你以为你们明白
You think you know...
牺牲的真正含义么
...what sacrifice really means?
星联告诉你们
Federation has thought you...
银河间不应存在冲突
...that conflict should not exist!
但是没有争斗
But without stronger,
你们永远不会明白你们自己的潜力
You'll never know who you trully are.
你根本不了解我们
You have no idea who we are.
但你马上就会明白了
But you'll soon find out.
你是想说你发送了求救信号，会有人来救你们么？
You mean the distress signal you thought you sent?
坐标已经被修改过了
The coordinates were altered.
你们的救援队会被困在星云里一无所获
Your rescue ships will be stranded in the nebula...
而你们的基地将会门户大开
...and your base left, full open.
原来你要袭击约克城号基地
You go to attack Yorktown.
数以百万计的来自星际联盟各个星球上的人
Millions of souls from every Federation world...
聚集在那里
...holding hands.
那是一个完美的目标
It's a perfect target.
你不会得逞的
You are wrong.
团结就是力量
There is strength in unity.
正是那些反抗的力量
The strength of others... Lieutenant...
让我能够活下去
... is what has kept me alive.
不！
No!
史波克
Spock!
史波克，你丫的醒醒！
Spock, wake up damn it!
医生，我现在很清醒
I am entirely conscious, doctor.
我只不过是在冥想，思考人生的自然规律
I am simply contemplating the nature of mortality.
你倒好，现在变成哲学家了
You feel philosophical, huh?
是因为失血过多脑子不太清醒吧
You have mass blood loss into that tria.
你曾问过我为什么和乌胡拉闹矛盾了
You asked me why Lt. Uhura and I parted ways.
考虑到瓦肯星已经被摧毁
I became concerned...
我越发的觉得
...in the light of Vulcans demise
我应该担负起聚集族人的责任
and would have had a duty to my species.
所以你要去传宗接代？
You thought you should be off making little Vulcans, huh?
我懂了，这让她很不安
Yup, I can see how that'd upset her.
我本来想跟她谈一谈这个问题
I intended to discuss it with her further
但我突然得知了一个对我触动很深的消息
but I received some news which affected me unexpectedly.
什么消息？
What news?
史波克大使去世了
Ambassador Spock is dead.
史波克，我很难过
Spock, I'm so sorry.
无法想象你有多么悲伤
I can not imagine what that must feel like.
如果你像他一样活了那么多年
When you lived this many lifes as he...
你就不会再畏惧死亡了
Fear of death is illogical.
对于死亡的恐惧
Fear of death...
是让我们活下去的动力
... is what keeps us alive.
我想活的像他一样充实
I don't want to live as he did.
这就是为什么我打算用我的余生
That is why I decided...
到新瓦肯星上
...to redirect my efforts and continue his work...
继续完成他的工作
...On New Vulcan.
你要离开星际舰队？
You are leaving Starfleet?
吉姆怎么想的？
What Jim have to say about that?
我还没找到合适的时间来跟他谈这个
I could not find the time to tell him.
我现在就能告诉你，他听到了你的想法肯定会不开心的
Oh, I can tell you he is not gonna like that.
不知道没了你，他会怎么办
Hell, I don't know what he'll do without ya.
你知道，如果我要走，他肯定搞个聚会就把我送走了
I mean, you know, me on the other hand.I would...I would throw a party.
老天，你已经神志不清了
My god, you get delirious.
我们离幸存者的所在坐标还有多远
How far are we from the coordinates from that call?
还有挺长一段路要走
Still a way, sir.
船长
Captain?
你什么时候开始怀疑她的
When did you begin to suspect her?
我怀疑的还不够早
Not soon enough.
你怎么会突然怀疑她？
How did you know?
也许是因为我嗅觉敏锐，能预知到危险吧
I guess you can say I got gut knows for danger.
快跑！
Run!
音乐？
Is that music?
这音乐从哪里放出来的？
Where the hell is that coming from?
那儿呢
There.
我把那个小盒子接到电源上，那个小口子就开始唱歌了
I found a middle box in the power cell and delivering mouth like it sing.
你真机智
That's very clever.
我觉得这音乐虽然比较老土
Music is a bit old fashion for my taste...
又吵，容易让人分心
...not to mention very loud and distracting...
但总的来说还是不错的
...but hey, well played.
我喜欢那节奏和呐喊
I like the beats and shouting.
是么？
Well you do.
- 把它关掉 - 没事的
- Switch it off. - Ah, it's okay.
快点关掉
Switch it off!
有人踩了我的陷阱
Someone set the foot on my traps.
船长？
Captain?
- 你认识他们？ - 是的，美女
- You know these men? - Ay, Lassie.
这位是帕维尔 契科夫
That's wemanel  is Pavel Chekov...
那位帅哥是詹姆斯 T.柯克
And that handsome bastard is James T. Kirk.
他们是我的朋友
They are my mates.
能见到你们真好
It's good to see you sir.
斯科特，她在干嘛
What is she doing Scotty?
别伤害他们
...don't hurt them because...
你自由了，詹姆斯 T.
You're free, James T.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott.
这位新朋友是谁？
Who's your new friend here?
- 真是红毯欢迎真是够隆重的- 这位是婕拉
- She should have throw out the welcome mat. - This is Jaylah.
我不知道你所说的红毯是什么东西
I do not know what is a welcome mat.
- 你找到其他人了吗？ - 没有，长官
- You found anyone else? - No, sir.
我很抱歉，就剩下我们几个了
I'm sorry. You are the only ones.
到底是怎么回事？为什么他们攻击我们？
What the hell happened up there, Jim?Why were we attacked?
他们在找我们从提纳兹星上带回来的手工品
They were after the artifact we brought back from Teenax.
- 他们拿到了么？ - 没
- Did they get it? - No.
- 你拿到了么？ - 没
- Have you got it? - No.
我还在进取号上的时候，我把它藏在了一个逃生舱里
It did get off the Enterprise when it was in the shuttle.
- 所以它在一个逃生舱里？ - 可以说在
- You hid it in a shuttle. - Yes.
也可以说不在
And no.
长官，这是富兰克林号星舰，是不是难以置信？
This is the USS Franklin, sir.Can you believe it?
第一艘能加速到曲速4的星舰
The first Earth ship capable of warp 4.
2160年在加加林辐射带消失
Lost in Gagarin radiation belt in 2160.
我在星舰学院学到过这艘飞船，船长是巴尔萨泽 爱迪生
I remember that from the Academy.Captain Balthazar Edison.
那是星际舰队成立的第一年，他的船怎么会跑到这？
It was his first year in Starfleet.How the hell did the ship end up here?
有很多种说法，长官
There is a lot of theories, sir.
有的说是被罗慕伦人抓走了
Surrended to the Romulans,
有的说是在太空中被一只绿色的巨手抓住了
Captured by a giant green space hand.
就我所认为的，它可能是通过虫洞传送到这来的
This farrer, must be a wormhole displacement.
你能发动这艘船吗？
Can she fly ?
飞船还缺几个驱动核心，电磁燃料也不够，长官
She is missing a few drive decoyls and EPS conduits are fried...
但是婕拉做了一些出色的修复工作，飞船系统重新上线了
but Jaylah has done a marvelous job getting the ship systems back online.
谢谢夸奖，蒙哥马利 斯考提
Thank you, Montgomery Scotty.
契科夫先生，你能不能利用船上的传感器
Mr. Chekov, Can you plug in the coordinates...
确认一下那个坐标附近幸存船员的位置？
...see if we can track the crews location from the ship's sensors?
是，长官
Ay, Captain.
他喜欢那个位置
He likes that seat.
斯科特先生，跟我四处看看
Mr. Scott, tour.
是，婕拉，我们走
Yes. The mess hall. Jaylah, get up.
好的
Yes.
我们到现在都不知道这些船员的下落吧？
No clue what happend to the crew, right?
是的，长官，他们已经死了有一个世纪了
No, sir. They would be dead 100 years by now.
那不是...
Is that...?
那是一台PX-70摩托车啊
That's a PX-70.
在我小的时候我爸爸就有一辆这样的摩托车
My dad used to have one when I was a kid.
我妈妈说他总会让她坐在后座然后就像疯子一样开始飙车
Mom saying back there it was driving her nuts.
长官
Sir.
婕拉说这个飞船一直在这，难道
If you tell me this things has been here this whole time and ...
其他人就看不到吗？
...no one has ever noticed it?
她在这个飞船上安装了图像折射器
She stand out the image reflectors.
- 就是所谓的全息伪装吧 - 是的，长官
-Alright, some sort of holographic camouflage. - Ay, sir.
长官
Captain!
我在星际舰队通信频道上
I intercepted a weak communication transmission, sir,
拦截到了一个微弱的求救信号
It's a Starfleet frequency.
传输检测
TRANSMISSION DETECTED
你能锁定信号发射的位置吗？
You can locate the signal?
可以，问题是我们要怎么去那里？
Yes, but how do we get to them?
长官，我有个想法，但是需要先征询您的意见
I have an idea, sir,but I'm gonna need your permission.
为什么一定需要我的批准
Why would you need my permission?
如果我搞砸的话
Because if I mess up,
我不想一个人背锅
I don't want it to be just my fault.
麦考伊和史波克呼叫进取号船员，收到请回答
McCoy and Spock Enteprise crew.Come in, Enterprise crew.
有人吗
Anyone.
撑住，史波克
Come on, Spock.
加油，你能做到的
Come on, we can make it.
医生，把我抛下能显著增加你的幸存几率
Leaving me behind will significantly increase your chances of survival, doctor.
这还要你说，但我决不会这么干的
Well, I stand sure that is completly out of question.
你现在的当务之急是找到其他幸存的船员
It is imperative that you locate any surviving crew.
我还以为你从来都不在乎我的死活呢
No, I am sticking with you, i don't care.
我当然在乎你，老骨头
Of course I care about...
我一直认为我对你的尊敬天地可鉴
I always assumed my respect for you is clear.
我们之间这么多年的谈话历历在目...
Dialogue we have had across the years...
别说了，史波克
It's okay, Spock.You don't have to say it.
至少我不会一个人孤零零的死去
Well, at least I won't die alone.
妈的这就是他的作风
Well, that's just typical.
王八蛋们，我跟你们拼了...
Come on...
医生，看到你没被大卸八块我很高兴
Good to see you in one piece doctor!
我在哪呢
Oh, am I?
我感觉我的肠子像被人扭过一般
I feel like my entrails were at barn days.
这些老式的传送机以前是用来运货的
I released old transporters were only ever used for cargo
我做了一些小调整，现在能传送人了
but a few modifications seems to do the trick.
但是我觉得最好还是一次传送一个人
I thought it was best to bim you one at a time
要不然传送的时候把你们俩绞在一起就不好了
You know, in case you got displaced.
我已经没法想象比这更糟糕的情况了
Oh, I couldn't imagine a worse scenario.
你能安全回来真好，没事吧？
Good to have you back.You all right?
我没事，他受伤了
Yeah, I'm fine. He's hurt.
船长，我身体很正常
I am functioning adequately, Captain.
才不是这样
In a pigs eye, you are.
船长，我们发现那个失踪的文物似乎是来自于这个星球
Captain, we discovered that a stolen artifact appears to come from this planet.
该死的，史波克！
Damn it, Spock!
- 这艘船上还有医疗设备吗 - 跟我来
- Are there any medical supplies on this thing ? - This way.
躺下
Lay down, come on.
这就对了
There you go.
史波克，我们要怎么离开这个地方？
How are we gonna get out of this hole, Spock?
我们没有
We got...
正常运行的飞船，也没有足够的船员
...no ship, no crew.
操作数据存储也不对
Not this ods..
吉姆，我们就像以前那样
We will do what we have always done, Jim.
在不可能中寻找希望
We will find hope in the impossible.
别急，先让你身体恢复再说
Let's get you patched up first, okay?
船长
Captain.
你必须集中你的注意力帮助船员
You must focus your efforts on helping the crew.
史波克，这就是我要你安心养病的原因
That's why I need you around Spock.
这些都是古代的玩意了
This thing is from dark ages.
拿过来试试看吧
Closer.
我确定这是一台原生质修复仪
I am pretty sure this is protoplaser.
能止住内出血，至少我希望如此
To stop the internal emergy. At least that's my hope.
都到死神门前了，他还在引用
It's miserable that we have no other medicine but only hope.
莎士比亚的名句
That quote is from Shakespeare.
航行日志，星历 2263.2
Captain's Log, Stardate 2263.2
我们同那边的人失去了联系
We searched the wreckage.
但还是不知道船长在哪
He must have hidden it elsewhere.
派我去完成任务吧
All we have is his crew, krall.
告诉我那东西在哪
Tell me where it is.
现在就告诉我！
Now!
No!
住手！
Stop!
放他走，我就把你想要的东西给你
Let him go and, I will give what you want.
不，希尔，别给他
No, Syl! Don't!
中尉
Lieutenant.
团结不是力量
Unity is not your strength,
而是弱点
It is your weakness.
我们要等到了解清楚以后再行动
We should wait until we are absolutely sure.
不，我们现在就着手准备尽快出发把船员救回来
No, we have to get the crew back, now.
既然契科夫已经找到了克劳基地的坐标，那我们就去
Chekov has the coordinates that can lead us to Krall's base, so we go.
恕我直言，先生，你怎么知道那个外星女人和克劳通话的时候克劳就在他的基地里
With respect, sir, how do we know that Krall was at the base when she called.
就算那时候他在基地里，我们也无法确定他是不是把船员关在他的基地里
And even if he was, we do not know if and the crew is with them.
连他们是死是活我们都不知道
Or still alive.
契科夫先生，你能根据这个公式
Mr. Chekov, Can you reconfigure the search parameters
调整一下搜寻参数吗？
in order to compensate for this formula?
可以，指挥官，但这个公式是什么意思？
Ay, Commander but, what is this forumla?
我的想法是从瓦克雅入手，它是一种瓦肯星上的特殊矿石
It is vokaya, Mr. Chekov.A mineral unique to Vulcan
能释放出低剂量的辐射射线
which emits a low-level radiation.
那么我就把其它的能量辐射都过滤掉吧
I'll have to find if there are any energy emissions.
史波克，你说的这个瓦肯矿石和我们这所讨论的问题有什么联系？
Spock, what the hell would a Vulcan mineral be doing way out here?
你打算怎么做？
Where are you going with this?
乌胡拉中尉戴着一个瓦克雅护身符
Lt. Uhura wears a vokaya amulet
它是我送给她的礼物，代表着我对她的爱和尊重
which I presented to her as a token of my affection and respect.
你送了一个有放射性的珠宝给你的女朋友？
You gave your girlfriend a radioactive jewelery?
辐射剂量很低，对人无害，医生
The emissions is harmless, Doctor.
但是它特殊的辐射信号让它极其容易被识别
But it's unique signature makes it very easy to identify.
你在你女朋友身上装了一个追踪装置？
You gave your girlfriend a tracking device?
那不是我的本意
That was not my intention.
还好你并不尊重我
I am glad he doesn't respect me.
找到了一个非常微弱的瓦克雅信号
I am detecting a very trace of vokaya.
这个坐标和之前从那个外星女人那里搞到的坐标相符吗，契科夫先生？
Does the location match the coordinates you acquired from Kalari, Mr. Chekov?
长官，坐标相符
It is a match, sir.
这表明乌胡拉中尉和其他船员现在
It's presence suggest that Lt. Uhura and thereby the rest of the crew
正被关在克劳的基地里
are being held at Krall's base of operation.
你能把他们传送出来么
Can we beam them out?
不能，长官，那边有一些地理干扰
No, sir. There is some geological interference
阻挡了传送信号
that is blocking transporter signal.
那么我们只能去那边一趟，用最原始的方法把他们救出来了
Well I guess we are gonna have to go and break in the old fashion way.
你们不能去那里
You can not go to this place.
去那边的人都死了
Everyone who goes there, he kills.
你去过那边？你亲眼看过？
You've been there? You've seen it?
姑娘，怎么从来没听你提过？
Why did you say something, Lassie?
因为我知道如果我说了，你们会让我带你们过去
Because I knew you will ask me to take you there.
你们的朋友在那边，那他们死定了，就像我的家人一样
If your friends are there then they will die,just like my family.
我绝不会回到那个死亡之地去
And I will not go back to that death place.
如果你能从基地里逃出来，那么你就能告诉我们怎么进去，怎么出来
If you escaped than you can show us the way in and the way out.
不！
No!
我们说好的可不是这样的 蒙哥马利 斯科特
This is not the deal we made, Montgomery Scotty.
如果你们执意要去 你们就自己去吧
If you choose to do this,you are on your own.
- 等等 - 让她走吧
- Wait, wait. - Let her go.
船长，她也失去过亲人
She's lost people too, Captain.
姑娘，我的朋友们被关在那边，我们可不能抛下他们啊
Wait, that's our friends out there Lassie,and we can not just leave them behind.
我们真的很需要你的帮助
We could really use your help.
你勇敢点就好
We just need you to be brave as all.
我还被关在那边的时候
When we run in that place...
克劳会时不时过来，带走一个人
... Krall will come in and take someone.
当时的那些惨叫至今在我的耳边盘旋
There were screams, I can still hear them.
我们再也不会见到被他带走的人
And we would not see that person again...
我们也不知道谁会是下一个
... it did not know who would be next.
我的父亲策划了一次逃亡行动
My father planned an escape.
但是被一个叫做
But we were seen by the...
玛纳斯的人发现了
...by the one they call Manas.
我的父亲和他扭打在一起，我有机会逃了出来
My father fought him so I could get out.
他很勇敢
He was brave...
却不幸惨死在玛纳斯手下
and Manas killed him.
你们想要做的事是不可能完成的
What you want is impossible.
也许我们能办到
Maybe it's not.
我的奶奶以前说过，众人拾柴火焰高
Maybe granny used to say "you cannot break a stick in a bundle".
姑娘，你是一个大的集体中的一员
You're a part of something bigger now, Lassie.
在困境中
Don't give on that...
我们绝不会放弃你
Because we are sur as hell, we'll never give up on you...
这也是我们团队一直以来的信念
That is what being part of crew is all about.
你也是这么想的么，詹姆斯 T.?
Is that what you believe in, James T.?
我只知道，跟你在一起我们成功几率会更大
All I know is, we stand a better chance with you.
这里有一条直通穴地的隧道
The diggind machines uncover the tunnel that goes into the crater
我就是从那逃出来的
That's how we get out.
我们就从那边潜入基地
Also that'll be our way in?
渗透小队在隧道的那一头待命
the away team will beam to the other side of the tunnel,follow it across to the base...
然后潜入基地，攻入内部建筑，救出船员
...get inside the building and break out the crew.
船长，我们无法锁定穴地里的任何人
Captain, we can not locate anyone inside the crater
更别说把他们传送上来了
in order to beam them out.
我会用信标增强信号
Or, I can bring up pulse beacons to path enhancers
- 这样就能收到穴地内部的信号了 - 好的
- That I get signal into the crater. - Alright.
富兰克林上的传送机一次能送上来多少人？
How many people can Franklin transport at the time?
我做一点调校，一次最多20人
With a minor modifications,20 max...
但是我不知道那老古董还能坚持多久
But I am not sure how long it will hold out.
老骨头，契科夫先生和婕拉，你们组成渗透小队
Bones, Mr. Chekov and Jaylah,would be in the away team.
斯科特先生，你负责修复传送仪
Mr Scott, modify the transporter
尽一切可能让它恢复正常
and do whatever you can to make this ship operational.
船长，考虑到契科夫先生的技术才能
Ay captain, Mr. Chekov's technical acumen
外勤过于危险，让他和斯科特先生一起待在富兰克林号比较合适
makes him more valuable onboard the Franklin with Mr. Scott.
我代替他更符合逻辑
Is there by logical that I would replace him.
胡说，史波克，你的伤刚刚好
Why is that logical Spock?You just got back on your feet.
乌胡拉中尉还被关在那里呢，吉姆
Lt. Uhura's in that facillity, Jim.
我会照顾好他的
I'll keep an eye on him.
那行吧
Understood.
基地到处都有他的卫兵把守，我们三个人就这么进去肯定会被发现
His soldiers are everywhere.We won't pass unseen.
我们需要人去吸引他们的注意力
What we require is a diversion.
我有个不错的想法
I think I have an idea.
这就是安布罗纳斯
This is Abronath.
古人把它们当做一种武器
It was used by the ancient once as a weapon
但是当他们发现自己无法驾驭它的力量的时候
But when they could not control its deadly power...
就把它分成了两半
...they split it into two...
把其中的核心部分扔到太空中
And rejected the halves into space.
希望它会永远的消失
Hoping it will be lost forever.
话说来我还得谢谢你们
But I am grateful
我毕生都在寻找它
I have spent life times searching for
而如今你们却替我找到了它
And only to have you find it for me.
真是命运无常啊
The poetry of fate.
我出生的世界
The world that I was born into...
和你们的不太一样，中尉
...is very different from yours, Lieutenant.
我们能感受到痛苦和恐惧
We knew pain, we knew terror.
正是斗争让我们更加强大
Struggle, made us strong.
不是和平，也不是团结
Not peace, not unity.
斗争是星联已经遗忘的强大力量
These are myths the Federation would had you believe.
这些说法
Those are strong words.
也许你自己深信不疑
You may even believe them.
但我感觉到你身上肯定还有一些说不清的东西
But there's something else
going on with you.
一些不为人知的东西
Something underneath.
等等
Wait.
你要干什么？
What are you doing with her?
你已经拿到了你想要的东西了，放她走
You already got what you want then Let her go!
不！
No!
玛纳斯
Manas.
It's time.
星联已经向外扩张了几个世纪了
The Federation has pushed the frontier for centuries.
我们会让他们就此停下扩张的脚步
But no longer.
中尉，这是我们斗争的开端
This is where it begins, Lieutenant.
这就是边境区域反击星联的开端
This is where the frontier,pushes back.
跟我来
This way.
她在哪？
Where is she?
这确实分散了他们不少注意力
I got to admit, that's a hell of a distraction.
你们的朋友被关在那边
Your friends are over there.
跟我来
Come on.
这里交给我
Let me deal with them.
你把这个带走
You've brought us this far.
完成我们的使命，克劳
Finish the mission, krall.
走
Go!
指挥官，乌胡拉被他们抓走了
Commander, Uhura they took her.
把船员带到安全的地方
Get ready and take the crew to safety.
快，我们走，跟上
Come on. Let's go. Move.
- 收到信号了，斯科特先生 - 好的，契科夫先生
- I've got them, Mr Scott. - Okay, Mr. Chekov.
分析信号，我们一次要传20人上来
Increase the signal.We are gonna grab them 20 at a time.
- 明白 - 希望我们不会搞砸
- Ay. - Let's hope this doesn't get messy.
传送仪充能
Energize!
史波克！
Spock!
你怎么会在这？
What are you doing here?
很明显，我是来救你的
Clearly,I am here to rescue you.
我们走
Let's go.
很高兴见到你，朋友
Good to see you, good man.
你会像你的父亲一样死在这的
You'll die here as your father.
医生，10秒钟后传送仪充能完成
Ten seconds until transporters recharged, doctor.
等我信号
Wait for my signal.
- 医生，不能再拖了 - 乌胡拉还没来我们不能走
- Doctor! - Damn it man, we are not leaving without them!
快，我们走
Come on! Let's go!
快走
Move! move!
我们已经准备就绪了，船长，把你的信标打开
We are ready for an extract,just turn on your beacon.
- 斯科特，所有人都接到了吗？ - 是的，长官
- Scotty, you have everybody? - Ay, sir.
除了你和婕拉都回来了
Everyones here except you and Jeylah.
打开信标，我们就把你传送回来
Start the beacon and we will grab ya.
你的朋友会把你扔在这的
They will leave you here.
船长，快打开信标
Captain, your beacon!
- 收到信号了 - 传送仪充能
- There it is! - Energize!
婕拉！
Jaylah!
再也别这么干了
Okay, let's never do that again.
我同意 詹姆斯 T.
I agree, James T.
你们还好吗？
You all right?
船长，他搞到的这个东西...
Captain this thing he has...
约克镇，他计划袭击约克镇
Yorktown. He is gonna destroy the Yorktown.
你们把我的房子拿去
You take my house...
把它开走
...and you make it fly.
斯科特，你能发动飞船吗？
Mr. Scotty, can you get this thing started?
你说什么？发动它？这个好说，但是让他飞起来，就是另外一码事了
Well start it, yes.Flying sir, that's a different thing.
这些老式的飞船是在太空建造的
These old vessel, they were built in space.
制造者们根本没打算让它们在大气层内起飞
They were never supposed to take off from the atmosphere.
不管怎么说我们得让它飞起来
Make it happen.
船长，它们被称作“星际飞船”是有原因的
They are called Starships sir,for a reason.
你为什么现在才跟我说？
You tell me this now?
我不想那么早告诉你，让你失望，万一你这次回不来怎么办
Because I didn't want to disappoint ya.You know, in case we didn't make it back.
斯科特先生，你可真是贴心啊
How thoughtful, Mr. Scott.
船长
Captain.
他已经起飞了
He is launching.
对约克镇的袭击说不定只是个开始
The attack at the Yorktown may be just the beginning.
用这种生物武器
With this bioweapon...
他可以杀死上面的所有人
...he could get rid of all life...
再利用基地里的先进科学技术
...and use the bases advanced technology...
来袭击各个星际联盟行星
...to attack an untold number of Federation planets.
我们得把这玩意开上天
We are just gonna have to get this thing flying.
长官，这可不仅仅是强制启动它那么简单的事
We can not just jump start it, sir.
所有系统已启动
Okay, all systems online.
锂反应炉充能70%，可用性正在增加
Dilithium chambers at 70% and raising.
次级引擎已准备完毕
Primary subwarp engines standing by.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
你能
You can...
让这东西
You know...
起飞的，对吧？
...fly this thing, right?
当然，你是在逗我么，先生？
You kidding me, sir?
太棒了
Fantastic.
斯科特，你那边怎么样？
Scotty, how are we looking?
长官，已经准备就绪
Ready as she will never be, sir.
就喜欢听你说这个，很好
That's what I like to hear.Alright.
老骨头，救回来的船员们怎么样了
Bones, where are we with the crew?
这边有个医疗舱还能用
I could use a functioning med bay,
大部分人身体状况良好
but otherwise we are secure down here.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu.
我们要将飞船开到最大临界速度
We have to achieve a terminal velocity,
稳定器才能成功托起飞船
in order for the stabilizers to provide lift.
你确定这台老式的推进器能办到吗？
Are you sure this drop is high enough to do that?
我们待会就知道了
We'll find out.
准备起飞吧，苏鲁先生
Call it, Mr. Sulu.
是，长官
Ay ay, Captain.
契科夫先生，听我口令准备启动稳定器
Mr. Chekov, be ready to hit the forward stabilizers
使用四分之一推力
full on my mark. One quarter impulse.
好
Right.
- 使用二分之一推力 - 明白
- One half impulse, Mr. Chekov. - Ay.
我们要系上安全带了，快走
We should belt up. Come on, move move!
稳点，苏鲁先生，别把飞船撞碎了
Easy, Mr. Sulu.Let's not break her now.
快使用全推力，苏鲁先生
Anytime, Mr. Sulu.
全推力，契科夫先生
Now, Mr. Chekov.
警报，不明舰艇正在靠近中
I have an alert on incoming vessel.
全频率未收到身份验证请求
No reply on all frequency ID request.
投到屏幕上来
Visual.
启动红色警报！
Red alert! Red alert!
看看他们发展的有多先进
Look how far they've come.
请注意警报
*Some kind of alert*
在各个频段上均收到了来自约克镇的求救信号
I'm picking up distress signals from every frequency coming from Yorktown.
克劳已经开始进攻了
Krall is already starting the attack.
斯科特，我们装备有哪些武器？
Mr. Scott, what kind of weapons do we have?
我们有相位脉冲炮和太空鱼雷
We have pulse phased cannons and spatial torpedoes.
很好，马上开火
Great. Lock and load.
这些武器对蜂群没用
That does not matter.You can no defeat the bees.
能暂时吸引他们注意力就行
Maybe, maybe we will lore them away.
我们得给约克镇上的人争取时间让他们躲到安全地带
How do we get Yorktown time to get people to safety?
我们的飞船太老了
We are on course and buggy competitors.
就这么冲进去我们自己也得粉身碎骨，船长
We are barely holding together as it is, Captain.
船长
Captain.
蜂群的飞行模式应该是由一位个体决定的
The flight paterns of bees are determined by individual decisions.
克劳的飞行器队形过于复杂
Krall's form formations are to complex...
如果不依赖某种形式的群体子网路算法就无法正常行动
...not to rely on some form of unified cyberpathic coordination.
- 所以我推断... - 史波克
- Assuming that we could be... - Spock.
直接告诉我结论就好
Skip to the end.
他想说的是，如果我们能让蜂群自乱阵脚
What he is saying that if we disorient the swarm...
就能击溃他们了
...we can kick it's ass.
我就这个意思
Precisely.
斯科特，你能不能把我传送到其中一架飞行器上去？
Scotty, can you beam me onto one of those swarm ships?
你这是疯了么？
Have you gone completly mad?
- 行还是不行？ - 不行
- Yes or no? - No.
行
Yes.
也许可以吧
Maybe.
船长，我熟悉这种飞行器的内部构造，这使得我
Captain, my familiarity with the interior of those ships, however brave
更加适合参加这次行动
makes me more qualified for this away mission.
史波克，你的伤还没好
Spock, you're still hurt.
史波克，她说的对
She's right, Spock.
我很感激你们对我的关心
I acknowledge and respect your concerns.
也许让一个对我的伤情和敌机都十分了解的人和我
Perhaps you will feel more confident if I were accompanied by someone
一起去你们会更加放心
with familiarity of both the ship and my injury.
他肯定很愿意跟你一起去
He is gonna love this.
你要我干什么来着？
You want me to do what?
快来吧，医生
Come along, doctor.
等等
Whoo, wait a minute.
你这个留着绿血，忘恩负义的混蛋，这都是你的馊主意
Why you green-blooded ingrain This was your idea.
老骨头，他这个主意还不错
It's a good idea, Bones.
下次如果有个管子扎到你腹部里了
You know, next time you have piece of pipes stuck in your trousers...
你就叫管道工帮你拔出来吧
...call a plumber.
一定要找到干扰他们队形的方式
Let's make sure you find a way to break these things.
如果你们遇上了什么麻烦，我就直接把你们传送回来
If it gets heady I'll beam ya straight back.
传送仪充能
Energize.
肯定会没事的
It will be great!
真该死，吉姆，我只是个医生，不是...
Damn it, Jim.I'm a doctor, not...
你难道不记得上次我开这玩意的时候
You do realize *something something*these things
我们坠机了？
we crash.
所以出了啥事别怪我...
*something*
我们撞到了什么
Hit something.
史波克呼叫富兰克林号
Spock by Franklin.
收到，史波克
Spock, we read you.
船长，就目前来看，敌机之间的确是用一种子网络语言
Captain, from what I can intricate, these ships do with the shared cyberpathic language...
相互沟通，协调行动的
...that coordinates their actions.
具体信息发给你了
Patching through now.
这就是那个信号
That's what they signalize.
原来他们不是在干扰我们，只是在相互沟通罢了
They weren't jamming us,they were talking to each other.
怎么才能让它们闭嘴呢
How do we get them to stop talking?
用电磁聚焦干扰怎么样？
What about an electromagnetic focusing?
我们可以发射信号干扰他们的通信
We can use the transporters to disturb their network.
干扰不一定要针对某个个体
Focus might be too specific.
如果我们能发送干扰信号扰乱蜂群的内部通讯
If you can plant some sort of disruptive communication signal inside the swarm
他们就无法相互沟通、协调，进而自乱阵脚
it might inversely effect capacity the way it coordinates.
这个干扰信号要用一个他们设想不到的频段发射出去
It will have to be the frequency they will not anticipate.
它会在蜂群内部引发连锁反应，进而摧毁整个蜂群
It will cause a chain reaction that will wipe out the whole swarm.
长官，这样一个密集的内部网络肯定对高频信号十分敏感
Sir, a closed network like that might be sensitible to very high frequency.
甚高频信号
VHF.
无线电
Radio.
我们可以通过飞船上发送一些广播信号
We can...We can broadcast something from the ship
来切断他们的通信网络
to wire out the links.
我们要播放一些又吵又令人分心的东西
Something loud and distracting.
又吵又令人分心？
Loud and distracting?
我刚好手上有这样的东西
I've got just the thing.
别把我的音乐播放器搞坏了
Do not break my music.
搞坏它？放心，不会的
Break it?It will get an upgrade.
60秒后他们就突进基地了
Swarm ships in 60 seconds will break in through.
我要重新配置多相高频信号
I just got to reconfigure the VHF array range multiphasic suite.
- 我来吧 - 别动，小姑娘
- Let me do it. - No, Lassie I am in a hurry.
快点
Do it.
看，就这样搞定了
There, see?
真简单
Simple.
好了
Alright.
船长，我们可以开始发送广播信号了
Captain, we are ready to broadcast.
这个信号传不太远，我们要把飞船开近一点
The signal won't travel far,we have to get closer.
- 开的多近？ - 越近越好
- How close? - Very.
规划拦截线路，苏鲁先生
Intercept course, Mr. Sulu.
是，先生
- *something*
我们的老朋友又来了
My old friend.
长官，蜂群正在聚集，形成攻击队列中
Swarm ships are gathering back and forming an attack wave, sir.
我们成功的吸引了他们的注意
I think we got their attention.
稳住，苏鲁先生
Hold steady, Mr. Sulu.
大家都打起精神来
Brace yourselves, everybody.
史波克，准备随时离开敌机编队
Spock, stand by to drop out of formation.
- 斯科特，你那边准备好了么 - 准备好了，长官
- Scotty, all queued up back there? - Ay, sir.
广播频率57.7兆赫兹
Ready to broadcast at 57.7 MHz.
- 姑娘，待会由你负责打开音乐 - 我就喜欢这种节奏和呐喊
- Made your choice, Lassie? - I have the beat and shouting.
让我们来制造点噪音吧
Let's make some noise.
这歌选的不错
That's a good choice.
开快点，医生，要不然我们会
Faster, Doc. We risk to be consumed
被它们的无规则移动撞到的
by the trajectorial defects.
你这个多嘴的后座乘客
Impact seat fibers.
- 小心点，医生 - 我知道
- Get ready, Doctor! - God damn, I see it!
他们在放古典音乐？
Is that classical music?
看起来的确如此，医生
Yes, Doctor.It'd seems to be.
乌胡拉中尉，让约克镇也用同样的频率广播
Lt. Uhura, make sure Yorktown has the frequency to broadcast.
长官，我们刚刚收到一条关于干扰敌机通信频率的情报
Sir, we now have the distraction frequency.
用该频率进行广播！
Broadcast!
你那边没事吧，史波克？
You're all right, Spock?
我们这边一切正常，船长
We are fine, Captain.
但是用三艘敌机已经突进了约克镇
But there are still three ships heading into Yorktown.
那肯定是克劳的座机
That's got to be Krall.
史波克，盯紧他们
Keep on him, Spock.
不惜一切代价组织他们使用生物武器
Do whatever it takes to stop him from using that weapon.
我的房子要塌了
My house is breaking!
再这样下去船壳要解体了
Mass depolarization of hull plating.
也许我能通过锂反应炉改变能量，但我需要帮助
Maybe I can redirect the power,
from the dilithium chamber, but I need help.
来帮我一把，婕拉，跟我走
I need you, Jaylah.Let's go!
医生，开快点，别跟丢了
Do not lose them, Doctor.
再吵就你来开，史波克
We can always change places if you want, Spock.
船长，想同时拦截三艘船几乎是不可能的
Captain, intercepting all three ships is an impossibility.
把约克镇的布局图调出来
Give me schematic of Yorktown.
他们肯定要去那，约克镇总部
There. Yorktown headquarters.
契科夫先生，能对中央广场进行一次生物污染物扫描吗？
Mr. Chekov, can you do a bioscan on central plaza?
好
Ay.
他们正在疏散平民
They are clearing civilians.
老骨头，前面有一个城市广场
Bones, there's a city plaza coming up.
想点办法，务必让他们经过那边
You have to make sure Krall heads for it.
- 为啥？ - 照做就是了！
- Why? - Just do it!
苏鲁，把我们送上去
Sulu, get us up there!
大家抓紧了
Hold onto something!
- 干得好，二位 - 谢谢长官夸奖
- Great work, Bones. - Thanks, Captain.
我现在在想我该如何降落这玩意呢
Now I just need to figure out how to land.
船长，船体有三处破损
Captain, I have 3 hull breaches from the impact.
分别位于3号甲板，货物舱和引擎室
Deck 3, the cargo bay and the engine room.
苏鲁和契科夫，你们去货舱和3号甲板检查一下
Alright, Sulu, Chekov, check the cargo bay and deck 3.
务必确保武器已经被销毁而且克劳也死了
I need confirmation that the weapon has been neutralized and that Krall is dead.
船长
Captain.
这是克劳干的，我们亲眼看过他把人吸干
It's Krall. We've seen him do this.
那是某种能量转移，同时也改变了他的外表
It's a somekind of energy transfer,and it physically changes him.
他可能还在船上，他们肯定是看到了他才被杀的
He must still be on board.No one seen him leave.
苏鲁，联系约克镇安全部门
Sulu, contact Yorktown security...
封锁这艘船
...to lockdown the ship.
我们走
Let's go.
船长
Captain.
开拓疆域
...expand the frontier...
那就是他
It's him.
斯科特，连接富兰克林号上的数据库
Scotty, I need you to link to Franklin database.
给我找到一切有关巴尔萨泽 爱迪生的信息
Find out what you can about Balthazar Edison.
- 富兰克林号的船长？ - 没错
- What the Captain on a Franklin? - Yes.
长官，他很久以前就死了
He is long dead.
不，我不知道他怎么办到的，但是爱迪生和克劳是一个人
No he is not. I do not know how,but Edison is Krall.
你发现了什么？
What did you find?
他的记录可以追溯到星联成立之前
Well, his records goes back when Federation didn't even exist .
他原先是一位来自于MACO的少校
He was a major in the United Earth Military Assault Command Operation.
那个组织多次卷入旧世界的战争
Along in the offworld combat.
- 他曾是一位军人 - 没错，先生，还是一位战功卓著的军人
- He was a soldier. - Ay, sir. And pretty good one.
MACO解散之后他的军事生涯也随之结束
His military service came to an end when MACO was disbanded.
为什么会解散？发生了什么事？
Why? What happened ?
星际联盟成立了，长官，后来还成立了星际舰队，我们又不是一个军事组织
The Federation sir, Starfleet.We are not a military agency.
星际舰队让他当上了富兰克林号的船长
They made him captain and gave him a Franklin.
- 斯科特，把他的日志调出来 - 是，长官
- Scotty, bring up his logs. - Ay, sir.
航行日志
Captain's Log...
直接翻到最后一条
The last record.
航行日志，我已经不记得星历了
Captain's Log....I don't remember the Stardate.
没人注意到我们的求救信号
All distress calls are nonsense.
船员也只剩下了三人
Of the crew, only 3 remain.
我会死在这的
I will only die.
这里的土生物种很久以前就放弃了这个星球
The indiginous race abandoned this planet long ago.
他们留下了很多复杂的钻探设备
They left behind sophisticated mining equipment
和大量的机群
and a drone platforms.
他们有一种特殊的科技
They had some sort of technology...
能延长我的
...that prolongs...
寿命
...life.
我会不惜一切代价为我和我的船员复仇
I'll do whatever it takes for me and my crew.
星联根本不在意我们的死活
The Federation do not care about us.
也许你们永远都不会再见到我了.
Probably never see me again...
但如果我出现在你们面前
...but if you do...
你们就准备受死吧
...be ready.
为什么他还没使用他的生物武器？
Why has he not used his weapon yet?
因为他想找一个能最大化其武器威力的地方来释放它
Because he wants to find somewhere to inflict maximum damage.
他需要一个空气流通系统
He needs a distribution system.
约克镇里有这样的系统吧？
Circulating area, right?
是的，先生，它的中心有一台大气调节器
Ay, sir. There's a atmospheric regulator core.
中尉，马上联系约克镇安全部门
Lieutenant, contact Yorktown...
没找到克劳之前，先把系统关闭
...make sure they shut it down before it finds Krall.
我要怎么才能去核心那边
How we access the core?
约克镇站重力核心附近有一座维修塔
Well, there is a maintenance tower at the stations gravitational nexus.
想去大气调节器只能通过那里了
That's the only way.
斯科特，你去约克镇总部，务必把它关闭
Scotty,get over there and make sure it gets shutdown.
美女，跟我来
Lassie, with me.
听我说，大气调节器是关不掉的
Look, this thing is impossible to shut down.
是么
Alright, well.
让我来试试看
Let's see about that.
斯科特先生，这玩意怎么还没关掉
Mr. Scott,why is that thing still on?
我们还在想办法，长官，但你应该明白我要突破很多安全协议
I'm working on that, sir, but as you can imagine there's a lot of safety protocols, so...
这个系统太结实了，你知道的，要不然会出事的
I need to think that you know keeps everybody alive.
赶紧想点办法
Find something out.
小心点，船长，你越靠近中心
Be careful captain.A gravity is gonna get a bit screwy...
重力的作用就越大
...the closer you get to the center.
我们应该扫描一下运行图，看看有没有后门
Maybe, we should scan the operations schematics.See if there is a backdoor.
姑娘，我要你帮我盯着屏幕
Lassie, I'm gonna need your eyes.
你在那都经历了些什么
What happened when you were out there...
爱迪生
Edison.
你居然知道我的原名？
Edison?
不得不说，柯克
I have to say Kirk
我很怀念过去的我
I missed being me.
我们三个人失去了人性
We lost ourselve,
但是达到目的了
But I gained a purpose.
我们找到了让银河系回归混乱的方法
It means to bring the galaxy extra trouble
让人类在抗争中变得更加强大
that makes humanity strong.
我觉得你误解了人性
I think you underestimate humanity.
我曾经为人性而战！
I fought for humanity!
在同新地人和罗慕伦人的战争中我们牺牲了数百万人
We lost millions with the Xindi and Romulan wars.
我们为了什么？
And for what?
难道是为了让我在星联的操纵下，坐在船长的位置上
For the Federation to sit in the captains chair.
同敌人握手言和？
And regret it with the enemy?
人是会改变的，而且我们必须那么做
We change. We have to.
否则我们就要一辈子争斗下去
We spend the rest of our lives fighting the same battles.
你已经输了
You lost!
你不可能过的去的
You no way you can make to get back there.
放弃吧
You are out.
就像你这个懦夫一样吗？
Like you did?
我读过你的航行日志
I read your simple log.
詹姆斯 T. 柯克船长
Captain James T. Kirk.
至少我还知道我是谁
Least I know who I am.
我是一位军人
I'm a soldier.
爱迪生，你为人类打赢了战争
You won the war, Edison.
你为我们创造了和平
You gave us peace.
和平
Peace...
我生来不是为了和平
It's not a world I was born into.
- 斯科特 - 船长
- Scotty. - Captain.
他在利用重力涡流滑行回到中心
He is using the gravitational slipstream to get back to the center.
不！
No!
武器已经激活了
Weapon's in the chamber.
船长，我们必须马上阻止他
Captain we have to stop the processor
要不然约克镇里所有需要呼吸的生物都死定了
or everything breathing in Yorktown is dead.
你没法阻止这一切
You can't stop it.
你死定了
You will die.
至少我是为了拯救生命而死
Better to die saving lives
比通过夺取他人性命让自己活着要好
Than to live with taking them.
这就是我活着的意义
That's what I was born into.
- 斯科特 - 长官，我想我能重新导引气流方向
- Scotty. - Captain, I think we can redirect it.
房间里有一个密封舱口
There's a seal construction, perhaps
打开阀门就能把武器排放到太空中
that will let you vent the weapon into space.
我可以在这边远程解锁，还需要你在那边手动操作阀门
Now we can override the locks, from out here,but you have to activate the hatch.
- 就是按一下按钮？ - 不是按钮，长官
- I just've to hit the button. - It's not a button, sir.
白色面板下面有一个把手
It's a simple lever under the white panel.
- 看到了 - 总共有四个
- Got it. - And there's 4 of them.
一旦你把舱口打开，你必须马上离开房间
Once you have activated lock,you've to exit the chamber immediately.
如果流通器正在运转，舱口打开，你还在那个房间里
If the hatch is opened when the CPU starts next cycle
你就会被吸入太空中
you are gonna get sucked into space.
如果我打不开舱口呢？
What happens when the hatch isn't opened?
你和生物武器都会被吸入一个流通系统里
You are gonna get sucked into big fan.
我们所有人都死定了
With the weapon and we all die.
该死的，吉姆，你恐怕没法按时出去了
Dammit, Jim, you won't make it out on time.
流通器打开了
The vent.
詹姆斯 T.,快走
Get out of there, James T.
动作快点
Scotty, the last hatch won't open.
- 斯科特 - 动作快点，船长，你还有8秒钟
- Scotty. - Work fast, Captain. Time is running out.
恐怕他搞不定了
He is not gonna make it.
没有你我该怎么办，史波克
What would I do without you, Spock?
（结案）
这么多年来，星联一直宣传说他是一位英雄
For decades,the Federation taught that he was a hero.
只有时间才能说明一切
I guess time would judge us all.
他是在太空中迷失了自我罢了
He just got lost.
柯克，你拯救了整个基地
You saved this entire base, Kirk.
挽救了数以百万的生命，谢谢你
Millions of souls. Thank you.
这不仅仅是我一个人的功劳，从来都不是
It wasn't just me. Never is.
我们考虑过你的申请了，你现在是舰队中将了
It's easy to say that the position of Vice Admiral, it's yours.
没人比你更适合这个职位
No one deserves it more.
舰队中将是不是不需要随舰航行?
Vice Admirals don't fly do they?
对
No.
不需要
They don't.
无意冒犯，女士
No offense, ma'am but...
那有什么好玩的呢？
...where's the fun in that?
你都没试着申请一下缩减任务时间？
You didn't even try to get our time reduced?
为啥要缩短任务时间？
Why would I get it reduced?
老骨头，我们现在可以去其它星云航行了
Bones, we know our way through the nebula now.
想想看我们在那边会发现什么
Can you imagine, what we'll find?
一心想着消灭人类的外星暴君？
Alien deathspots,Calvenom killing us.
致命的外星病菌？
Deadly space worm, viruses and bacteria.
还是瞬间能把我们消灭于无形的宇宙异类？
Incomprehensible cosmic anomalies that could wipe us out in an instant.
那多有意思啊
It's gonna be so much fun.
顺便问一句，我们这是要去哪来着，我还以为我们要去喝一杯呢
By the way, where're we going?I thought we were gonna get drink.
我记得你曾经让我保密，但是...
I know you told me to keep it under wraps, but...
生日快乐！
Happy birthday!
感觉如何？
Mr Sensitive ?
谢谢你，斯科特
Thanks, Scotty.
各位，举起手中的酒，敬我们的船长詹姆斯 T.柯克一杯
Everybody raise your glass to Captain James T. Kirk.
- 柯克船长 - 谢谢各位
- Captain Kirk. - Thanks, everybody.
- 敬进取号... - 敬进取号...
- To the Enterprise... - To the Enterprise.
和我们逝去的朋友
...and to absent friends.
干杯
Cheers.
派对开始喽
Alright, let's get this party started.
我还以为你要先写完你的任务报告
I thought you have to finish your mission report.
我本来是那么打算的
I do.
但是我觉得和你一起参加社交活动能让你更开心
But I thought it would be more pleasing to engage with you socialy.
你的恋爱套路真是老套
You old romantic.
你知道吗，苏格兰威士忌其实是由一位年轻的俄国女士发明的？
Do you know that scotch was actually invented by little lady in Russia?
抱歉失陪一下
Excuse me.
你一个人喝了这么多？真令人惊讶
Did you drink all those yourself?I am impressed.
有人告诉我说喝这个能让人放松
Someone said that it will take my edge off.
喝了这么多我还是不觉得轻松
My edge is still not off.
也许这个能让你开心点
Alright, gold, maybe this will help.
船长找了点关系
Captain pulled a few strings.
如果你愿意的话，你可以加入星舰学院
That is acceptance into Starfleet Academy,if you want to.
那儿的条条框框很多
We have a lot rules.No less, no more.
我是不是必须穿那个制服？
Will I have to wear that uniform?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
你好，昆赛尔
Hey, Keenser.
凯文，你终于开始穿裤子了？
Kevin, is there no way to wear pants?
我听说了史波克大使的事
I heard about Ambassador Spock.
上次在电梯里
Is that what you wanted to mention...
你就想跟我说这个？
...that time in the turbolift?
差不多吧
More or less.
我想你和帕里斯指挥官的会面进行的十分顺利吧
I trust your meeting with Comandant Harris went well.
差不多吧
More or less.
你是不是很渴望继续到太空中航行？
You really want to head back out there, huh?
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是进取号星舰的旅程
These are voyagers of the starship Enterprise.
她正在进行的任务，是去探索这未知的新世界
It's continuing mission to explore strange new worlds...
探索新的生命形式和发现新的文明
... To seek out new life and new civilizations...